radicalislam.org 2019-11-15

# Privacy Policy | Clarion Project

**Updated: December 2018**

Clarion takes your privacy seriously. We are committed to protecting your privacy and security and have explained in detail the steps we take to do so. We urge you to read our privacy policy.

Clarion Project, Inc. (“Clarion”, “us”, “we”, “our”) owns and operates [https://clarionproject.org](https://clarionproject.org/) (the “Site”). This privacy policy informs the user (“you”) of the Site’s privacy policy regarding the collection, use, disclosure, retention, and protection of personal information received from users of the Site. It applies to any Clarion site or application, service or tool (collectively “Services”) where this Privacy Policy is referenced, regardless of how the user accesses or uses them, including through mobile devices. **By using our Services and/or our Site, you accept and agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy and the User Agreement, and consent to the collection, use, disclosures, retention, and protection of personal information as described in this Privacy Policy.** **This is our entire Privacy Policy for the Site and it supersedes any earlier version.   You agree to it every time you use the Site.**

 **PERSONAL INFORMATION**

When you voluntarily provide it, we collect personal information in the course of interacting with the site. “Personal Information” is information that can be associated with a specific user and could be used to identify that specific user whether from that data or from that data and other information that Clarion has or is likely to have access to. We do not consider personal information to include information that has been made anonymous or aggregated so that it can no longer be used to identify a specific person, whether in combination with other information or otherwise.

You do not have to provide Personal Information to browse the Site. However, you may voluntarily send us information from the Site, including Personal Information. At the Site you are able to subscribe to an email newsletter, sign up for a course, sign up to watch video content, sign up for email, take part in reader feedback, participate in polls or surveys, ask questions, send feedback or make a donation. In so doing, you may be asked to provide Personal Information such as your name, address, e-mail address or mobile number. Contact information, such as name, email and phone number, and demographic information, such as zip code, may be gathered from our visitors from information requests or other forms.

 **COLLECTION AND USE OF DATA**

When you visit the Site, we automatically receive information from your browser or mobile device such as your browser type (e.g., Firefox, Internet Explorer, etc.), the operating system of your device (e.g., Windows or Mac OS), the URL of the site from which you came and the URL of the site you visit when leaving the Site.  We also receive your IP address (Internet Protocol set of numbers called Internet Address) and the name of your ISP or your mobile carrier.  Depending on your device’s settings, we may also receive location data and other types of information sent from third-party services or GPS-enabled devices.  As you use the Site, we may also collect information about such usage and your actions on our Site, such as pages you viewed, access times, and how long you spent on a page.  We may use cookies to collect such information, as described in more detail below. We may use this information to analyze the design and functionality of our site in order to make site improvements. We may use such information in the aggregate to analyze site usage.

We may use the information you give us to provide services to you, at your request, including but not limited to Clarion’s educational, networking, marketing, social, recruiting activities, donation processing, store payment processing, and for other similar business purposes. We may use it to communicate with you through periodic messages regarding services, events, and other information and notices to provide you information regarding news, political or legal developments we believe may interest you. We may use it for confirmation of donations, registrations, or other actions you take on our site, and for related customer service needs. We use information you provide about others to enable us to send them referral notices, videos you choose to share or other such services. We only use contact information to send information requested or to contact users as necessary.

In certain instances, we may share your Personal Information with third parties such as our co-promotional partners and others with whom we have marketing or other relationships who assist Clarion in carrying out the above-mentioned business functions. Clarion may also share Personal Information and other data with its service providers, which may include, contractors, consultants and vendors, to help us perform statistical analysis, send you email, newsletters, marketing material, postal mail, provide customer support, arrange for deliveries, operation of the Site technology, internal operations, marketing services, and other related services; unless you have opted-out of such sharing with these service providers. Except as provided in this Privacy Policy, our Terms of Use, or as set forth when you submit the information, your Personal Information will not be shared or sold to any third parties without your prior approval.

To enable payment for purchases in our store and donations, we collect and store name, address, telephone number, email address, credit card information and other billing information. This information will only be shared with third-parties who help to complete the purchase transaction. Examples of this include fulfilling orders and processing credit card payments.

Clarion keeps track of the pages you visit within the Site for statistical purposes, marketing, site optimization, operational decisions, and law enforcement purposes.  This data may also be used to deliver customized content within the Site.

Non-Personal Information is any information that is not Personal Information. Clarion may combine Non-Personal Information you provide through the Site with information from other users to create aggregate data. Aggregate data does not (i) contain any information that could identify you, or (ii) include your personal contact information.

If you do not want us to share your information with our contractors and service provider, as described above, you can direct us not to share that information by contacting us.  An opt-out of information sharing will not apply to information sharing arrangements described in the Compulsory Disclosure section of this policy.

 **COMPULSORY DISCLOSURE**

Clarion will disclose your Personal Information, without notice, for the purpose of preventing criminal activity or disclosing criminal activity, or any other wrongful conduct. Clarion will also disclose your Personal Information if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to:

(a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on Clarion or the Site, specifically, (i) when required or advised to do so in response to a valid legal requirement, such as a state or federal law, regulation, search warrant, subpoena, or court order; or (ii) when we suspect criminal or wrongful conduct by a visitor of the Site; or (iii) in special cases, such as in response to a physical threat to You or others, to protect property, or assert legal rights or defend ourselves in litigation;

(b) protect and defend the rights or property of Clarion; (c) comply with a governmental regulation or lawful demand; and

(c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of Clarion, or the public.

If we are legally compelled to disclose your Personal Information to a third-party, we will attempt to notify you unless doing so would violate the law or a court order or result in a potential danger to the public or an individual.

 **USER GENERATED CONTENT**

If Clarion makes available to you the ability to comment on content from the Site, post content to the Site, or publish content on a third-party website through a link on the Site, then any information you post will be visible to the public and any Personal Information you post may be read, collected and used by third-parties that are not obligated to the terms of this Privacy Policy.  Clarion is not responsible for any information you share about yourself to the public through the Site and Clarion has no responsibility to remove or edit information you publish or post to the Site.

Further, through the use of APIs that we may utilize, any information you post or publish on or through the Site may be available on other websites or blogs.  Clarion is not responsible for any personal information you choose to make public through posting or publishing content on or through the Site, and you agree that such sharing of information will be deemed to have been done by you, not Clarion.

 **EMAIL SUBSCRIPTION LISTS**

Clarion offers a subscription list service to its visitors that you can opt-in to. We will never subscribe you to any mailing list without your request or agreement. If you are subscribed to any lists, we provide the ability to opt-out of receiving these communications from us by following the instruction listed in the email. If we feel that we have provided you with a valuable service and you may want to support us we may send you a periodic solicitation email, which you can unsubscribe from at any time. We will never pass on your email address to a third party or send you spam.

 **OPTING-OUT**

We respect your privacy and ability to choose whether to share information with us and any third party. If you receive communications from us that you prefer not to receive, you may request to opt out from receiving these communications by contacting us as indicated in the Contact Us section below.

 **CAN-SPAM COMPLIANCE NOTICE**

Clarion fully complies with the federal CAN-SPAM Act.  You can always opt out of receipt of further email correspondence from us.

 **COOKIES**

Our Site makes limited use of cookies. “Cookies” are small text files that are stored on a local computer hard drive that contain information related to your use of a site. A Cookie can’t read data off of your computer hard disk or read Cookie files created by other websites. Cookies do not damage your system. Cookies help websites provide visitors with customized features. Our site uses Cookies to deliver content specific to your interests, location, and for other purposes. You can choose whether to accept Cookies by changing the settings of your Internet browser. You can reset your browser to refuse all Cookies or allow your browser to show you when a Cookie is being sent. If you choose not to accept these Cookies, your experience at our site may be diminished and some features may not work as intended.

In order to optimize the Site, we may allow other authorized third-parties to place or recognize unique Cookies on your browser. Any information provided to third-parties through Cookies will not be Personal Information, but may provide general segment information to enhance your user experience by providing more relevant marketing. Third-party services and tools we use and which may send Cookies to users of the Site, and to collect certain information from Users, include:

 _Google Analytics:_ Google Analytics collects information such as how often users visit the Site, what pages they visit when they do so, and what other sites they used prior to coming to the Site.  We use the information We get from Google Analytics only to improve the Site.  Google Analytics collects only the IP address assigned to you on the date you visit the Site, rather than your name or other identifying information.  You can review Google’s privacy policy at <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>.  We do not combine the information collected through Google Analytics with Personal Information.  Although Google Analytics plants a permanent Cookie on your web browser to identify you as a unique user the next time you visit the Site, the Cookie cannot be used by anyone but Google.  Google’s ability to use and share information collected by Google Analytics about your visits to this Site is restricted by the Google Analytics Terms of Use and the Google Privacy Policy.  You can prevent Google Analytics from recognizing you on return visits to the Site by disabling Cookies on your browser (see below).

 _DoubleClick and DoubleClick Bid Manager_ : DoubleClick and DoubleClick Ad Exchange Buyer (operated by DoubleClick) collect anonymous data (ad views, browser information, Cookie data, date/time, demographic data, hardware/software type, internet service provider, interaction data, page views, and serving domains), pseudonymous data (IP Address (EU PII), search history, location based data, Clickstream Data, PII (name , address, phone number, email address, login, EU- IP address, EU-unique device ID ), sensitive (financial information). DoubleClick’s and DoubleClick Bid Manager’s privacy policy can be found at: <https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/>.  Aggregate data is shared with third-parties.  Anonymous data is shared by third-parties.  Clarion does not combine the information collected through DoubleClick or DoubleClick Bid Manager with Personal Information.

 _Facebook Social Plugins:_  The Face Social Plugins are operated by Facebook.  The Facebook Social Plugins collect anonymous data (ad views, analytics, browser information, Cookie data, date/time, demographic data, hardware/software type, internet service provider, interaction data and page views), pseudonymous data (IP Address (EU PII), Device ID (EU PII), PII (name, address, phone number, email address, EU- IP address, EU-unique device ID), sensitive (financial information). Aggregate and anonymous data is shared by Facebook with 3rd parties.  The Facebook Social Plugins’ privacy policy can be found at:  <https://www.facebook.com/full_data_use_policy>.

 _AddThis:_ AddThis is operated by AddThis, Inc.  The AddThis plugin collects anonymous data (analytics, browser information, Cookie data, date/time, demographic data, and page views), pseudonymous data (IP Address (EU PII), search history), PII (name, address, phone number, email address), Aggregate data is shared by AddThis, Inc. with 3rd parties.  The AddThis privacy policy can be found at: <http://www.addthis.com/privacy/privacy-policy>.

 _Vimeo:_   Vimeo Inc. provides a platform for publishing and viewing video content within a webpage.  Vimeo, Inc. collects data, which includes Cookies and statistical usage data.  Vimeo, Inc.’s privacy policy can be found at:  <https://vimeo.com/privacy>

 _Authorize.net:   _Authorize.net provides payment processing services for Clarion.  As part of a transaction to purchase products or services from Clarion, Authorize.net collects Personal Information that you provide to it during checkout, it collects data through Cookies and it collects statistical usage data.  Authorize.Net’s privacy policy can be found at:  <https://www.authorize.net/company/privacy/>

Each of the above-listed services and tools listed is governed by the privacy policy established by the respective third-party provider.  We encourage you to refer to such policies, which are linked to above in the description of each service.

Some browsers may allow you to manage the storage of Cookies on your device.  If supported by your browser, you may set your browser to refuse all Cookies (or, sometimes all third-party Cookies) or to alert you when a Cookie is set.  However, if you select these settings, you may be unable to access certain parts of the Site.  Unless you have adjusted your browser setting to refuse Cookies, our system will issue Cookies.  For more information about how to manage your Cookies preferences, use the ‘help’ menu of your web browser or explore the customer support sections of your web browser.  To opt-out of all Cookies or certain advertising Cookies, visit the company website for your browser.

Your browser may provide you with the option to send a “Do Not Track” signal to websites you visit.  This signal is used to request that websites not send the requesting device cookies, but websites have no obligation to respond to such signal or to modify their operation.  At the current time, the Site is not programmed to recognize Do Not Track signals, so the Site will not treat you differently if we receive such signals from Your browser and we may not comply with Do Not Track settings on Your browser.

 **SECURITY**

The security of your personal information is important to us but remember that no method of transmission over the Internet or method of electronic storage is 100% secure. We protect your information using technical and administrative security measures to reduce the risks of loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure and alteration. Some of the safeguards we use are firewalls and data encryption, physical access controls to our data centers, and information access authorization controls. If you believe your account has been abused, please contact us following the instructions in the Contact Us section below.

 **EXEMPTIONS FROM PRIVACY POLICY**

Our Privacy Policy does not apply to any information you may send to Clarion by email or instant messaging programs (e.g., AOL, Yahoo, etc.), or through social media networks, even if You open such programs or services by clicking a link displayed on the Site.  Email, social media, and instant messages are not recognized as secure communication forms.  Please do not send any information You consider private to Us by email or instant message or through social media sites (e.g., Twitter, Facebook, etc.) due to the public nature of such postings.

 **TRANSFER OF OWNERSHIP**

If ownership of the Site changes, whether in whole or in part, information collected through the Site about you may be transferred to the new owner so the Site and any service provided through or related to the Site can continue.  In that case, your user information would remain subject to the terms and conditions of Our then current Privacy Policy.

 **NOTICE TO RESIDENTS OF COUNTRIES OUTSIDE OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA**

Clarion is headquartered in the United States of America.  Personal Information may be accessed by us or transferred to us in the United States or to Our affiliates, business partners, merchants, or service providers elsewhere in the world.  Your information collected through the Site may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which Clarion or its affiliates or service providers maintain facilities. Clarion may transfer information that it collects about you, including personal information, to affiliated entities, or to other third-parties across borders and from your country or jurisdiction to other countries or jurisdictions around the world. If you are located in the European Union or other regions with laws governing data collection and use that may differ from U.S. law, please note that Clarion may transfer information, including your personal information, to a country and jurisdiction that does not have the same data protection laws as your jurisdiction, and you consent to the transfer of information to the U.S. or any other country in which Clarion or its parent, subsidiaries, affiliates or service providers maintain facilities and the use and disclosure of information about you as described in this Privacy Policy.

Information, which may or may not include Personal Information, may be accessed by Clarion or transferred to Clarion in the United States or to Clarion’s affiliates, business partners, merchants, or service providers elsewhere in the world.  By providing Clarion with Personal Information, you consent to this transfer.

We will protect the privacy and security of Personal Information according to Our Privacy Policy, regardless of where it is processed or stored.  If you do not consent to having your information processed and stored in the U.S., please do not provide it to Clarion.

 **CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS**

Under Section 1798.83 of the California Civil Code, residents of California can obtain certain information from companies with whom they have an established business relationship.  That information is about the Personally identifiable information those companies have shared with third-parties for direct marketing purposes during the preceding calendar year.  The law requires companies to inform consumers about the categories of Personal Information shared with third parties, the names and addresses of those third-parties, and examples of the services or products marketed by those third-parties.  To request a copy of the information disclosure provided by Clarion under Section 1798.83 of the California Civil Code, please contact us via email to [privacy@Clarionproject.org](mailto:privacy@Clarionproject.org).   Please allow 60 days for a response.

 **CHILDREN’S PRIVACY PROTECTION**

Clarion takes special care to protect the privacy needs of children under the age of 13 and Clarion encourages parents to be an active participant in their child’s online activities.  Clarion abides by the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) and other relevant laws.  The Site does not target and is not intended for children under the age of 13, and Clarion will not knowingly collect Personal Information from them.  If Clarion discovers personal data from a child gathered through the Site, Clarion will eliminate that data.  This Site is not intended for persons under the age of 18.  If you are under 18 you must ask a parent or legal guardian for permission prior to submitting any information to this Site.

 **ACCESS**

If you are an individual you may have certain rights under applicable data protection legislation, including the right to review and correct the personal data we hold about you.  Unless you reside in California or another jurisdiction that requires us to provide the information without charge, we may charge you a fee to receive a copy of this data.  For a copy of or reasonable access to your personal data, please contact us.

 **EUROPEAN UNION DISCLOSURE**

Personal Information voluntarily submitted to Clarion online, via electronic communication, or otherwise, may be maintained or accessed in servers or files in the United States of America, which the European Union has not deemed to provide “adequate” privacy protection.  If you do not consent to having your information processed and stored in the United States of America, please do not provide it to Clarion.

 **CHANGES TO PRIVACY POLICY**

This Privacy Policy is effective as of the date first noted above and will remain in effect except with respect to any changes in its provisions in the future, which will be in effect immediately after being posted on this page.

We reserve the right to update or change our Privacy Policy at any time and you should check this Privacy Policy periodically. Your continued use of the Service after we post any modifications to the Privacy Policy on this page will constitute your acknowledgement of the modifications and your consent to abide and be bound by the modified Privacy Policy.

If we make any material changes to this Privacy Policy, we will notify you either through the email address you have provided us, or by placing a prominent notice on the Site.

 **CONTACT US**

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, please contact us at:

Clarion Project, Inc.  
2020 Pennsylvania Ave NW  
P.O. Box 395  
Washington DC, Washington DC 20006  
Phone:  855-433-1422  
Email: [privacy@clarionproject.org](mailto:privacy@clarionproject.org).
